Join now by Browns assistant general
manager Glenn Cook and Glenn, this is
what months and months and perhaps you
could even say year of work goes into
tonight as we get ready to start the
2026 NFL Draft. What are you just
feeling like right now? Like let's go.
>> It's time to go. Ready to go. Yeah. Uh
it's been and we usually count count our
extra months. So, it's been about 13
months. So,
uh we're excited. We got two picks. So,
it's it's time to get this thing going.
Um I'm ready. From a board standpoint,
the hay's in the barn. The chaos could
come from phone calls that maybe you
expected or maybe phone calls even that
you didn't expect. Yeah, I mean
Yeah, there there's been contact. We
One, we're checking in to make sure we
have the right phone numbers. I I said
this to you earlier. And then two, yeah,
you know, teams are checking in. There's
this little bit of a jockeying happening
right now. But, um it'll really get
intense probably as the picks start to
come in uh when the draft starts at the
beginning since we're at the top.
>> All right. So, what is this phone
process like? Like who is there a magic
phone when it rings, you know somebody's
calling for a trade? So, everybody gets
all excited. How does that actually
work?
>> usually know who the contact is at the
other team. And uh so, you know, when
that number comes through, you know,
it's someone from, for example,
Carolina. You know, and they're calling
and saying, "Hey, you know, uh maybe
they're checking to see
>> Is there a special trade phone that's
just for tonight? We use our cell
phones. Everyone has a you know, a hard
line in just in case uh
something's weird going on with with the
phone service. But, yeah, uh it's
However you need to reach them, you
reach them uh just to check in. So. All
right. 6 and 24. Yeah. Two picks in the
first round here tonight. For now. Maybe
there could be more. Maybe who knows
what's going to happen. But, how does
that kind of change the approach if at
all knowing that finally you guys have
some of those real valuable assets to go
and and bring great football players to
this team?
>> for us it's been really important to
make sure we stick to
our plan, the way we prepare cuz you
don't want to change how you prepare
just because the amount of picks you
have. But, it does give us a little bit
more uh
a few more options, right? Like just a
few more options whether we want to
trade up, trade down, you know, sit and
take two really good players. So, it
opens up um a couple opportunities that
when you just have one are not there
without you creating it. So, uh it'll be
fun. It'll be fun. Without giving too
much away, give a little peek to the
people who are watching about the
scenarios that you guys go through and
prepare with to so that tonight when
you're on the clock cuz you only have so
much time that you're able to make those
decisions quickly and know that this is
a decision that maybe we've already
confronted and made.
>> Yeah, I think to your point, it's you
know, there's 8 minutes on the clock and
the the worst position to be in is is
sitting there with about a minute and a
half to go and have no idea or have not
necessarily thought through this one
scenario and and how you would uh decide
around it. So, we try to vet as many
different whether it's quirky or way
outside the box or even just within our
wheelhouse. Just try to work through as
many of those as a team ask hard
questions, push on different decisions,
push on different thinking and it you
know, for us it opens up some stuff we
hadn't thought about, right? Like, "Oh,
okay, this is an interesting um
opportunity or if this player is there,
we you know, we don't want to have not
thought about this before we we we get
to that pick." So, it's really just
working out the kinks. And no different
than anything, you want to prepare,
prepare, prepare, you know? Um
opportunity comes to the prepared mind
and we want to be prepared ready to go.
Is this one of the times of the day when
you're done with me, you know, here as
you're going to get ready and the draft
is going to be starting imminently? Is
this where people are kind of lobbying
for their final second, "These are my
guys." or is all that lobbying done?
>> Not here, right? Like I think, you know,
uh Andrew's made a lot of space for
everybody to speak and contribute and we
we work together here. It's big on we're
big on trying to collaborate on all
these decisions. So, now it's like I'm
going to get a workout, I'm going to
eat, and and you know, hopefully they
start this thing off on time and we get
ready to go. All right. Well, Glenn,
good luck tonight. Get us some good
players and let's go Browns.